<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Auto-regressive models | Pedro F da Costa</title>
    <link>http://pedroferreiradacosta.github.io/tag/auto-regressive-models/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://pedroferreiradacosta.github.io/tag/auto-regressive-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Auto-regressive models</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Pedro F da Costa</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 15:44:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://pedroferreiradacosta.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Auto-regressive models</title>
      <link>http://pedroferreiradacosta.github.io/tag/auto-regressive-models/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normative Modelling in Psychiatry</title>
      <link>http://pedroferreiradacosta.github.io/project/normative-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 15:44:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pedroferreiradacosta.github.io/project/normative-modelling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div style=&#34;text-align: justify&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is challenging to successfully train deep learning classifiers when the researcher only has access to small datasets or when the number of features of the input data is large. Both of these are the case for neuroimaging data. It is rare to find datasets with more than a couple thousand examples and this number is even lower for datasets of specific brain disorders.
One different approach that bypasses this issue is building normative models of the brain and measure these disorders as specific out-of-distribution examples  in a process of anomaly detection. One effective way to build normative models is using auto-regressors, that learn to map inputs to outputs while reducing the data in a middle bottleneck layer. This leads to the model reducing the large feature number of the data to a more manageable number that can be studied as a common distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a first project I contributed to, we developed an adversarial auto-encoder to distinguish mild-cognitive development and Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease and compared the results to classical predicitve models working on the original data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class = &#34;btn btn-outline-primary btn-page-header&#34; href=&#34;https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.02.10.931824v1.full.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;fas fa-file-alt  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Paper &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class = &#34;btn btn-outline-primary btn-page-header&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/Warvito/Normative-modelling-using-deep-autoencoders&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-github  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Code &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a second project, we are using state-of-the-art VQVAEs to reduce brain data into a quantized latent space and using transformers to measure the likelihood of the given distribuiton of the data. This is being used to identify psychiatric disorders. This work is still in development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
